- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
*
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[tropical music]
[热带音乐]
*
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
I wish to register
a complaint.
我想注册
投诉。
- [growling]
- [咆哮]
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
An urchin!
一个顽童！
- Yuck!
- 恶心！
- Hey lady, take your infested
patty with you.
- 嘿女士，带走你的感染者
帕蒂和你在一起。
Okay, no need to panic,
Squidward,
好的，不用惊慌，
章鱼哥，
It's just a puny urchin.
这只是一个微不足道的顽童而已。
Everything's gonna be fine
as long as you...
一切都会好起来的
只要你...
smash it! Smash it!
Smash it!
粉碎它！粉碎它！
粉碎它！
[groans]
[呻吟]
Phew.
唷。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[moaning]
[呻吟]
- [gasps]
Squidward, I'm surprised at you.
- [喘气]
章鱼哥，你让我很惊讶。
That little urchin
wasn't hurting anyone.
那个小顽童
没有伤害任何人。
He's still one
of Neptune's creatures,
他还是一个人
海王星的生物，
no matter how small he is.
不管他有多小。
This is where the magic happens,
little urchin.
这就是神奇发生的地方
小顽童。
First we turn up the heat,
首先我们把火调大，
but don't make it too hot.
但不要让它太热。
Would you like to see
a menu, monsieur?
你想看吗
菜单吗，先生？
[laughing]
- [growling]
[笑]
- [咆哮]
- Ow!
- 噢！
- [chittering]
- [叽叽喳喳]
- Okay, little guy,
see you later.
- 好吧，小家伙，
稍后见。
Good thing he is
a little guy.
还好他是
一个小家伙。
Ouch.
哎哟。
Ah!
啊!
[whimsical music]
[异想天开的音乐]
*
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
* *
**
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
*
What the shrimp?
什么虾？
Hey, what's going on here?
嘿，这是怎么回事？
Whoa! That's too hot!
哇！太热了！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Whoa!
哇！
Wow.
哇。
Oops.
[chuckles]
哎呀。
[笑声]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[whimsical music]
[异想天开的音乐]
* *
**
I steamed myself tiny.
我把自己蒸得很小。
- Whoo-hoo!
I steamed myself tiny!
- 呼呼！
我把自己蒸小了！
Whoo!
呼！
This place is huge!
这个地方很大！
[gasps]
[喘气]
My spatula's huge.
我的锅铲很大。
And just look at the size
of my grill.
只看尺寸
我的烤架。
It's huge!
太大了！
[bell ringing]
Ow!
[铃声响起]
噢！
[humming]
[soft music]
[嗡嗡声]
[轻音乐]
*
Ow! Ow ow ow ow ow!
噢！呜呜呜呜呜！
Ahh!
啊！
Ahh.
啊。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Come on, flip.
来吧，翻转。
Wha--[grunts]
什——[咕哝]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
[laughing]
[笑]
Uh-oh, the grill blew out.
呃哦，烤架炸了。
Well...[sniffs]
it isn't going to fix itself.
嗯...[鼻子]
它不会自行修复。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
That's one small step
for SpongeBob,
这只是一小步
对于海绵宝宝来说，
one giant leap for...
Wee!
为……迈出一大步
威！
Whoa.
哇哦。
Bob.
鲍勃.
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Whew.
Oh!
呼。
哦！
- [crying]
- What is that?
- [哭泣]
- 那是什么？
- [crying]
- [哭泣]
- Hey,
it's my little urchin friend.
- 嘿，
这是我的小顽童朋友。
Aww, hey, little guy.
Don't cry.
哇哦，嘿，小家伙。
别哭。
Your old pal "Wee-Bob"
will get you out of there.
你的老朋友“Wee-Bob”
会带你离开那里。
[groaning]
[呻吟]
[groans]
Little urchin, you are
free to go. You okay?
小顽童你是
可以自由去。你还好吗？
- [roars]
- [咆哮]
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Yeouch!
哎呀！
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
- [roaring]
- [咆哮]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [chomping]
- [咀嚼]
- Wah!
- 哇！
- [blubbering]
- [哭泣]
- Sorry, little guy.
- 对不起，小家伙。
Whoa!
哇！
both: Whoa!
两人：哇！
- Whoa! Whoa!
- 哇！哇！
- Follow the pipes to freedom,
little guy.
- 跟随管道走向自由，
小家伙。
I'll never forget you.
我永远不会忘记你。
[grunts]
Really.
[咕哝]
真的。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[bell ringing]
Ow!
[铃声响起]
噢！
What is all that noise?
这些噪音是什么？
[bell ringing]
- One Krabby Patty!
[铃声响起]
- 一份蟹肉饼！
- Coming right up!
- 马上就来！
[whimsical music]
[异想天开的音乐]
- Urchin!
Smash it! Smash it! Smash it!
- 顽童！
粉碎它！粉碎它！粉碎它！
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Ah-ha!
- 啊哈！
You're getting sloppy,
Plankton.
你越来越邋遢了
浮游生物。
Squidward almost squashed you.
章鱼哥差点把你压扁了。
[laughing]
[笑]
Back to the bucket with ya!
和你一起回到水桶吧！
- No! No, Mr. Krabs,
it's me!
- 不！不，蟹老板先生，
是我！
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Ooh. [chuckles]
That tickles.
哦。 [笑声]
那很痒。
- Well, SpongeBob SquarePants.
- 好吧，海绵宝宝。
it looks like you lost
a little weight.
看来你输了
有点重。
- Oh, hi, Karen.
Where's Plankton?
- 哦，嗨，凯伦。
浮游生物在哪里？
- You landed on him.
- 你落在他身上了。
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
- Hi, Plankton.
- [grunts]
- 嗨，浮游生物。
- [咕哝]
"Spongeboob?"
Why are you so small?
“海绵宝宝？”
你怎么这么小？
Is this a trick?
这是一个诡计吗？
- Calm down, he's clean.
I frisked him.
- 冷静点，他很干净。
我搜身了他。
- I didn't mean to get small
like you, Plankton.
- 我并不是故意变小
就像你一样，浮游生物。
It was a freak accident.
这是一次离奇的事故。
- Huh?
Who are you calling a freak?
- 啊？
你说谁是怪胎？
Wait a second.
[chuckles]
等一下。
[笑声]
Hold this.
[grunts]
拿着这个。
[咕哝]
[squeals]
[gasps]
[尖叫声]
[喘气]
You're not small like me,
shorty.
你并不像我那么小
矮个子。
I am a towering half
a millimeter taller than you.
我是高耸的一半
比你高一毫米。
I win!
[laughing]
我赢了！
[笑]
- Hooray!
- [groaning]
- 万岁！
- [呻吟]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- I'll get that.
- Don't touch that!
- 我会明白的。
- 别碰那个！
[groaning]
[呻吟]
- Oops.
- 哎呀。
- Get him out of here,
Karen!
- 带他离开这里
凯伦！
- Way ahead of you, chief.
- 远远领先于你，酋长。
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
- Cool.
- 凉爽的。
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
[indistinct chatter]
[模糊的喋喋不休]
[spits] Ha ha!
I found an action figure.
[吐口水]哈哈！
我找到了一个可动人偶。
- Whoa.
I saw it first.
- 哇哦。
我先看到的。
- No, I did.
- Finders keepers.
- 不，我做到了。
- 发现者和守门员。
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- What's the matter with you?
- 你怎么了？
- Blech.
- 布莱赫。
- It's got my spit on it.
-上面有我的口水。
- Whoa!
You can't catch me.
- 哇！
你抓不到我。
[laughing]
[笑]
[kids shouting]
- Don't let him get away.
[孩子们喊叫]
- 别让他跑了。
[all murmuring]
[大家窃窃私语]
- [laughing]
- [grunts]
- [笑]
- [咕哝]
This is the best
action figure ever.
这是最好的
有史以来的动作人物。
- [panting]
- [snoring]
- [气喘吁吁]
- [打鼾]
- SpongeBob
in the corner pocket. Doink!
- 海绵宝宝
在角落的口袋里。多因克！
[all grunting, yelling]
[所有人咕哝，大喊]
- You brats get back
in the play area
- 你们这群臭小子快回来吧
在游乐区
or I'll 86 your face!
不然我就86你的脸！
- [blows raspberry]
- [吹覆盆子]
Bang, bang, bang, bang,
bang, bang, bang.
砰，砰，砰，砰，
砰，砰，砰。
[laughing]
[笑]
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
all:
We want our action figure back.
全部：
我们希望我们的人偶回来。
- Ow!
- 噢！
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- Krusty Krab action figures
aren't free, you know.
- 蟹堡王可动人偶
不是免费的，你知道。
So get your parents' money
and you can have it.
所以要拿父母的钱
你可以拥有它。
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- Uh, Eugene, we don't sell
action figures.
- 呃，尤金，我们不卖
动作人物。
- Hmm.
- Peek-a-boo!
- 唔。
- 躲猫猫！
- [gasps]
- What the--[moans]
- [喘气]
- 什么--[呻吟]
- SpongeBob,
what are you doing in my hand?
- 海绵宝宝，
你在我手里做什么？
And why aren't you back there
flipping patties?
你为什么不回来
翻转肉饼？
- Sorry, Mr. K,
I shrunk myself by mistake,
- 对不起，K先生，
我不小心把自己缩小了
but I won't let it
affect my job.
但我不会让它
影响我的工作。
I will get back to flipping
right now.
我会重新开始翻转
现在。
Hold on there, tiny.
坚持住，小小。
I can't have you working
the grill no more.
我不能让你工作
不再是烤架了。
Too dangerous for a little guy
like you.
对于一个小家伙来说太危险了
像你一样。
- Oh, please, Mr. Krabs, there
must be some job I could do.
- 哦，请，蟹老板先生，在那儿
一定是我能做的一些工作。
I don't care what it is.
Please, please, please?
我不在乎它是什么。
拜托，拜托，拜托？
- All right,
I'll think of something.
- 好吧，
我会想点办法。
But since you're so small now,
但既然你现在还这么小，
I can only pay you
a penny...a year.
我只能付钱给你
一分钱……一年。
- Whoa!
- 哇！
That's big money.
那是一大笔钱。
Ow!
- Hmm.
噢！
- 唔。
Now, what could I do
with a little SpongeBob?
现在，我能做什么
和一个小海绵宝宝？
Oh, hmm.
[grumbles]
哦，嗯。
[抱怨]
- Personal hygiene service?
- 个人卫生服务？
[all talking at once]
[大家同时说话]
- Roll up your sleeves,
boy-o.
- 卷起袖子，
男孩-o。
You're a personal hygienist now.
您现在是一名个人卫生员。
- Whoo-hoo! Yay!
- 呼呼！耶！
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
- Ahh!
- 啊！
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
- Right there, yeah.
- 就在那里，是的。
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- Ahh.
- 啊。
[toilet flushes]
[厕所冲水]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Whew.
呼。
- Break time, SpongeBob.
- 休息时间，海绵宝宝。
Take five,
but hurry back.
拿五个，
但快点回来。
You gotta start earning
that penny.
你必须开始赚钱
那一分钱。
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- Hmm. Work the register,
clean the windows,
- 唔。工作登记册，
清洁窗户，
make the patties.
做肉饼。
I have to do everything now.
我现在必须做所有事情。
Thanks a lot, "ShrinkBob."
非常感谢，“收缩鲍勃”。
[screaming, grunting]
[尖叫，咕哝]
- It's okay, Squidward.
I'll make the patties for y--
- 没关系，章鱼哥。
我会为你做馅饼--
Oh, yeah, I forgot.
哦，是的，我忘了。
I'm too little.
我还太小了
Boy, I'm really going to miss
my old job.
男孩，我真的会想念
我的旧工作。
- Lunch rush is over,
Mr. Squidward.
- 午餐高峰结束了，
章鱼哥先生。
Now, wash those dishes!
- [growling]
现在，洗那些盘子！
- [咆哮]
- "Lunch rush is over,
Mr. Squidward.
- “午餐高峰结束了，
章鱼哥先生。
Now, wash them dishes."
现在，给他们洗碗。”
- [muffled yelling]
- [低声喊叫]
The bubbles are
making me bigger.
气泡是
让我变得更大。
More bubbles!
更多气泡！
- What the?
[grunts]
- 什么？
[咕哝]
- Thank you, Squidward.
- 谢谢你，章鱼哥。
I'm big enough
to flip patties again.
我够大了
再次翻转肉饼。
[shouting]
[喊叫]
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
- Whoa!
- [screaming]
- 哇！
- [尖叫]
[all groaning]
[全都呻吟]
- Mr. Squidward!
Call the fire department!
- 章鱼哥先生！
打电话叫消防队！
- No need to call them,
Mr. Krabs.
- 无需打电话给他们，
蟹老板。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
We'll be there in five minutes
depending on traffic.
我们五分钟后到
取决于交通情况。
[laughing]
- Make a left at the light!
[笑]
- 在红绿灯处左转！